in this video we're going to talk about
polygons a polygon with three sides is
known as a
triangle a polygon with four sides is a
quadrilateral now if we're dealing with
regular polygons all four sides are
congruent and all angles are the same
which makes this particular
quadrilateral a
square a five-sided polygon
is known as a
pentagon and a polygon with six
sides is known as a
hexagon a polygon with eight
sides is known as an
octagon so those are some common names
that you want to be familiar
with now let's say if we have a regular
pentagon
what is the
measure of an interior angle inside a
pentagon the first thing you need to do
is find the sum of all the interior
angles in a polygon and you could use
this formula it's N - 2 * 180 where n
represents the number of sides in a
polygon in a pentagon there are five
sides so n is
five so the first thing you want to do
is subtract 5 by two which is three and
then take that number multiply it by
180° so the sum of all five angles in a
pentagon is
540° now to find the interior angle
which we can call X take the total angle
and divide it by the number of sides so
we're going to divide it by
five 500 ID 5 is 100
40 / 5 is 8 so 540 / 5 is 100 + 8 or
108 so that's going to be the measure of
each interior angle inside a
pentagon so every angle that you see
inside of it is
108° with a total angle of
540 so now it's your turn find the
measure of each interior
angle inside a
hexagon so first we need to find the sum
of all interior
angles so let's use the same Formula nus
2 *
180 a hexagon has six
sides 6 - 2 is 4 so then this is 4 * 180
which is
720 so now we're going to take 720
and divid by the number of sides of a
hexagon which is
6 72 / 6 is 12 so 720 ID 6 is 120 so
that's the measure of each interior
angle
inside the hexagon every angle is
120°
for